AYUSH RANJAN

+61-402484302 St. Kilda East, Melbourne. <u>ayushranjan15@gmail.com</u>. **Portfolio website** (https://ayushranjan15.github.io)

Data Analysis and Exploration | Database (SQL) | Python | Web API | Writing and Communication skills | AWS

PROFILE

A trained data scientist with strong analytical and programming skills in Python, SQL and java. I understand the importance of customer service by my experience in data science consultancy and retail. Have utilise lean principals of agile software development.

PROJECTS

Ames Housing Price Prediction App

Designed a web app for Kaggle competition, challenging to build a regression model capable to give accurate predictions(lowest MSE). Analysed data and engineered features, trained and compared different regression models to select the best ones. Build an UI for the model and deployed it on AWS. Ranked in top 39% among 60K participants.

Spotify song recommender app

Designed a web app integrated with Spotify API, that recommends songs from a target playlist given a source playlist. The app uses cosine similarity to find most similar songs based on aggregated source playlist vector.

Predicting students iteration rate

Analyse and model students enrolment data to predicting the possibility of a student dropping out after 1st year of studies. Tested and compared different classification models based on accuracy score.

EDUCATION

RMIT UNIVERSITY — Masters of Data Science — 2019 - 2021(Expected)

Manipal University Jaipur, India — B.Tech Electronics and Communication — 2014 - 2018

EXPERIENCE

Analytics Consultant Intern, Redwood analytics; Bangalore, India — June 2018 - August 2018

- Performed EDA (Exploratory Data Analytics) on data provided by the client and presented insights to the stakeholders.
- Help identify different clusters in data to device adequate marketing strategies/products for clients.

Intern, Dia Capital Advisory; Bangalore, India — February 2018 - August 2018

- Supporting team in operations.
- · Market research and Presentations.